Hello and welcome to this extra posted broadcast on the occasion of the great notice that is happening right now.
Yes, the Coronavirus affects the labor market very heavy and many companies unfortunately have to notify or leave their employees.
Today I have Annika Sundén, Head of Analysis, and Mats Rubertson, qualified manager here at the Employment Service.
You are warmly welcomed here.
Thanks so much.
I thought we might start by sorting out what warning actually means.
Annika, what does it mean to be notified today
A notice is that it is a company that tells its employees
And what with layoffs right now is that this
is a crisis that we know will end.
It is a virus that will disappear
And then the companies want
What is important is that the companies remain when this has blown over or when the virus does not exist
And therefore it can be good for a company to permit to be able to keep its employees,
To be able to start then when the wheels start rolling again.
Luminals are something that has always existed and
that is an agreement between employers and employee organizations
And now there is also the possibility of short -term work
which is handled by the Growth Agency that makes it more advantageous
If we take care and care as you mentioned
so it is a sector where there is a very high demand
And a lot of people are needed in sick and health care and care right now.
We have seen that more job ads have been received for those jobs.
So one thing to think about right now is that if there is something one would like to do in the future
which you can now educate.
After all, there is a great need in care and care.
So to start thinking about an education within it.
Yes a great point there.
Mats, layoffs we have to go back to it.
Are there any figures on what it looks like with layoffs
The layers have 500650 pieces?
Yes 650 pieces, there are not so many yet but we expect many more.